Guide to the Carolee Schneemann Papers M1892
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Carolee Schneemann papers
circa 1954-2012
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
M1892
128 Linear Feet 226 boxes (189 manuscript boxes, 31 flat boxes, 12 cartons, 4 oversize folders)
The papers of Carolee Schneemann chronicle in detail her work as an artist, film maker, writer, art historian, feminist, and teacher.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
A portion of this collection was purchased by Stanford University Libraries in 2012; the remainder was a gift.
Conditions Governing Access
Collection is open for research use except for the diaries in Subseries 5.3. which are restricted until 5 years after Schneemann's death. Audiovisual materials are not available in original format, and must be reformatted to a digital use copy.
Related Materials
The Getty Research Institute also holds a significant archive of Schneemann material, mostly devoted to her earlier years: http://archives2.getty.edu:8082/xtf/view?docId=ead/950001/950001.xml
Scope and Contents
Artist Carolee Schneemann was born October 12, 1939 in rural Pennsylvania. Her art, which primarily involves performance, film, painting, and installation, has largely focused on sexuality, gender, and the body, and she is considered part of the first generation of feminist artists.
Schneemann's work emerged from the 1950s-60s avant-garde surrounding Fluxus, Judson Hall and New York's dance, poetry, new music and happening scenes, but it quickly staked out a distinct territory of its own. Schneemann has stated that she considers what she does as an extension of painting, only freed from the canvas. Using her body as a collage element, she explores themes including physicality, dimensionality, and kinetics. Among the works most central to the establishment of her reputation for the uncompromising and iconoclastic are the following three:
Meat Joy (1964) is a performance involving eight partially clothed figures moving in materials including wet paint, sausage, raw fish and chicken, and scraps of paper. It was first performed in Europe and was later filmed and photographed as performed by Schneemann's Kinetic Theater group at Judson Memorial Church. Fuses (1964-1967) was Schneemann's exploration of heterosexual sex from a female perspective, using footage of her lovemaking with partner James Tenney which was then treated and edited in various ways, superimposing natural scenes and painting in a collage-like effect. Interior Scroll (1975) was first performed in East Hampton, New York and Colorado's Telluride, and featured Schneemann solo, first striking various figure modeling "action poses," then reading from her book Cézanne, She Was a Great Painter, and finally drawing forth from her vagina a three-foot scroll from which she read aloud.
Although these works have been invoked, recalled, and reinterpreted many times by Schneemann since their creation, this collection focuses more on her more recent projects. Her own writing and notes dominate, but there is a significant amount of correspondence, including printed and annotated email exchanges. One of the main series is devoted to project files, which begin around 1990. These have not been physically arranged, and in most cases folder titles were transcribed directly from the original. Printed material about Schneemann includes exhibit and event publicity as well as reviews and criticism. Of the many photographs and slides, most document her art and its evolution, as do the audiovisual media. There are also lecture and workshop notes, scrapbooks, research files, and book preparation material, especially for Correspondence Course, An Epistolary History of Carolee Schneemann and Her Circle edited by Kristine Stiles. There is even a small number of costume/environments as used in her performances.
- Series 1. Project files, bulk
  Scope and Contents
  The Project files series consists of Schneemann's day-to-day correspondence concerning various projects in the 1990s and 2000s. These projects include exhibitions, performances, lectures, publishing, teaching and workshops, film screenings, and other endeavors. Although the majority is correspondence (annotated by CS, especially with printed email), there are also notes (including concepts and ideas for art), reviews, interviews, contracts, itineraries, and drafts of programs and catalogs. Most of the communication is with curators and gallery staff, her assistants, other artists/collaborators, students, academics, journalists, and friends, and involves negotiation, logistics, and other planning. There is no over all chronological order to the series, but the original order per box has been retained. Folder titles and contents were also kept intact, with some names normalized. Many folders have other unrelated material, and some titles may not represent contents or date ranges.
  - Location One (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Bruce McPherson - Jamie Gordon (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Robert Kelly Celebration Anthology, 2011-05 (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Iowa, 2005 (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - Iowa, 2011 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - WCA [Women's Caucus for Art], 2011-02 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Francesco Conz (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Vanishing art (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Portland, 2011-02 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Lawrence Brose, 2010 (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Taipei - Cameron (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Warhol Museum, 2006-05 (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Gallery Akinci, 2005-02 (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - Tenney, 2005 (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - Over with, 2005-2006 (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - Follow up, 2004 (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - Anne de Villepoix (Box 37, Folder 13)
  - Grants, 2002 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Grief (Box 30, Folder 16)
  - Paintings ICI (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Feminisms & Its Discontents, 2002 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Steve Baker (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - UK (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Contacts WACBIZ (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Archive (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - RISD Crisis Response show (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Whitney, 1999 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Child drawings, 2005 (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - Elga Wimmer (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - Grant applications, 1995-1996 (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - 1960s performance images (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Miroslav Rogala ICS, Instructions Per Second (Box 42, Folder 2-4)
  - Alan March Folder (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Interviews (Box 44, Folder 11)
  - Butterfly Madonna (Box 44, Folder 12)
  - By C.S. [New York memories etc.] (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - Work statements (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Section II [chapter typescript] (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Mixed notes (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Fluxus 90s Walkert (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - California, 1991-1997 (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - articles, coursepacks (Box 46, Folder 1-2)
  - Jen Barker notes, 2005 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - WACBIZ/Suzanne Hilleary (Writers & Artists Cooperative) (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Bruce Martin (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Texts - Reference [some by CS] (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - DC 2008/Hirshorn 2004-5 (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - Go Away, 2009 (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - Reina Sofia (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - misc. exhibit material, 2006 (Box 46, Folder 10)
  - Consignment (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Agreements - Permissions Long term (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Photo permissions (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Artist's Rights Society (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Marielle Nitoslawska/Brakhage screening permission, 2004-2005 (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Sagamie [Montreal] (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Cliff Eyland (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Ottawa, 2005-01 (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - Canada (Box 47, Folder 9-11)
  - P.P.O.W. (Box 47, Folder 12-13)
  - Sensorium [Boston], 2006 (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Finland (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - London (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - MIT (Box 48, Folder 4-5)
  - Recommendations/CS appointments (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Under way, 2007-2009 (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - Marjorie Keller (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - Jack Tilton gallery (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - Grey Art Gallery (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Writing Women (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Iceland, 2006-11 (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - Guggy [Guggenheim], 2005 (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Eye Body edition, 2004 (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Venice, 2007 (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - Buffalo CEPA - MOCCA/Ontario etc., 2007 (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - CEPA catalog mockups "Split Decision" (Box 49, Folder 8-9)
  - Bern, 2008-12 (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Norway, 2008-12 (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Denver Film Festival, 2008 (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Milwaukee, 2008 (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - Pierre Menaud gallery, 2007-10 (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - Rutgers, 2006 (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - WACK: Art and the Feminist Revolution MOCA, 2007-2008 (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - Berlin, 2008-12 (Box 50, Folder 8)
  - misc. correspondence etc., 2007-2008 (Box 50, Folder 10)
  - Donnell Library - film (Box 50, Folder 11)
  - Known/Unknown, 1996 (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Film brochure layouts (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - MOCA Hall of Mirrors [reviews] (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - Body As Membrane Denmark/Finland, 1996 (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - Vienna, 1995 (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - Canada/Western Front/Pacific Cinematique/UBC, 1995 (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - Mortal Coils, 1994 (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - Michelle Rhodes masters thesis "Performance Art As Therapy Practice" (Box 51, Folder 8)
  - Rosanna Chiessi/Kent State, 1990 (Box 62, Folder 5)
  - Emily/Italy/Paris, 1990 (Box 62, Folder 6)
  - Key Gallery, 1992 (Box 62, Folder 7)
  - London, 1992 (Box 62, Folder 8)
  - Turner-Krull, 1993 (Box 62, Folder 9)
  - Exhibitions, 1993 (Box 62, Folder 10)
  - Exhibitions, 1994 (Box 62, Folder 11)
  - Pace Roberts Foundation, 1994 (Box 62, Folder 12)
  - C.G. Pompidou, 1994 (Box 62, Folder 13)
  - California, 1997 (Box 63, Folder 1)
  - Leonardo, 1994 (Box 63, Folder 2)
  - Canada, 1995 (Box 63, Folder 3)
  - Denmark, 1995 (Box 63, Folder 4)
  - Projects, 1995 (Box 63, Folder 5)
  - Anti-Demeter, 1995 (Box 63, Folder 6)
  - Capp St. Project, 1995 (Box 63, Folder 7)
  - Vienna, 1995 (Box 63, Folder 8)
  - Paris, 1995 (Box 63, Folder 9)
  - MOCA, 1996 (Box 64, Folder 1)
  - Pompidou, 1996 (Box 64, Folder 2)
  - Projects, 1996 (Box 64, Folder 3)
  - Hubert Klocker, 1996-2000 (Box 64, Folder 4)
  - Galerie Krinzinger, 1996 (Box 64, Folder 5)
  - Musee de Marseille, 1996 (Box 64, Folder 6)
  - Paris, 1996 (Box 64, Folder 7)
  - New Museum, 1996 (Box 64, Folder 8)
  - Al Hansen - Kolinisches Stat Museum, 1996 (Box 64, Folder 9)
  - Rose Lee Goldberg, 1997 (Box 65, Folder 1)
  - Winnipeg, 1997 (Box 65, Folder 2)
  - Frauen Museum, 1997 (Box 65, Folder 3)
  - Banff Centre for the Arts, 1997 (Box 65, Folder 4)
  - Adrian Heathfield, 1997 (Box 65, Folder 5)
  - Denmark, 1997 (Box 65, Folder 6)
  - Turner- Krull, 1997 (Box 65, Folder 7)
  - Bard exhibit, 1997 (Box 65, Folder 8)
  - Chicago, 1997 (Box 65, Folder 9)
  - Joan Hotchkis, 1997 (Box 65, Folder 10)
  - Boston, 1997 (Box 65, Folder 11)
  - Projects, 1997 (Box 65, Folder 12)
  - New Museum, 1997 (Box 65, Folder 13)
  - Wexner, 1997 (Box 66, Folder 1)
  - MOMA, 1998 (Box 66, Folder 2)
  - Carolyn Eyler/University of Southern Maine, 1998 (Box 66, Folder 3)
  - Jay Dunn, 1998 (Box 66, Folder 4)
  - New MOCA, 1998 (Box 66, Folder 5)
  - Ryerson, 1998 (Box 66, Folder 6)
  - Le Lieu, 1998 (Box 66, Folder 7)
  - Linda Weintraub - Roberto Edwards, ArtCORPUS, 1998 (Box 66, Folder 8)
  - Beyond Baroque, 1998 (Box 66, Folder 9)
  - Kip Stroud/Arcadia Summer Art Program, 1998 (Box 66, Folder 10)
  - Pollack-Krasner Foundation, 1997-1998 (Box 66, Folder 11)
  - Vienna, 1998 (Box 66, Folder 12)
  - Dinnerware Gallery, 1998 (Box 67, Folder 1)
  - Farley-Speyer, 1998 (Box 67, Folder 2)
  - Title Nine, 1998 (Box 67, Folder 3)
  - MAC-BA, 1998 (Box 67, Folder 4)
  - Pori Art Museum, Finland, 1998 (Box 67, Folder 5)
  - Chicago, 1998 (Box 67, Folder 6)
  - LA MOCA, 1998 (Box 67, Folder 7)
  - Huttinger/Shiffler, 1998 (Box 67, Folder 8)
  - Colorworks, 1998 (Box 67, Folder 9)
  - Finland, 1999 (Box 67, Folder 10)
  - Art Table, 1999 (Box 67, Folder 11)
  - Maryland, 1999 (Box 67, Folder 12)
  - Tokyo, 1999 (Box 67, Folder 13)
  - Boston, 1999 (Box 67, Folder 16)
  - Washington University, 1999 (Box 67, Folder 14)
  - Bob Griffin, 1999 (Box 67, Folder 15)
  - Rutgers, 1999 (Box 67, Folder 17)
  - MOCA, 1999 (Box 67, Folder 18)
  - Art Pace, 1999 (Box 67, Folder 19-20)
  - Barcelona, 1999 (Box 68, Folder 1)
  - Winnipeg, 2000 (Box 68, Folder 2)
  - Peter Fend, 2000 (Box 68, Folder 3)
  - College Art Association Conference, 2000 (Box 68, Folder 4)
  - Gasser & Grunet, 2000 (Box 68, Folder 5)
  - Richard Herskowitz, 2000 (Box 68, Folder 6)
  - Illinois, 2000 (Box 68, Folder 7)
  - Sweden, 2000 (Box 68, Folder 8)
  - Munich, 2000 (Box 68, Folder 9)
  - Norway, 2000 (Box 68, Folder 10)
  - Musee de L'Elysee Lausanne, 2000 (Box 68, Folder 11)
  - Cornerhouse, 2000-2001 (Box 68, Folder 12-13)
  - England, 2000 (Box 69, Folder 1)
  - New Zealand, 2000 (Box 69, Folder 2)
  - Women Dallas, 2000 (Box 69, Folder 3)
  - Denmark, 2000 (Box 69, Folder 4)
  - East Hampton, 2000 (Box 69, Folder 5)
  - Calendar 2000 Project (Box 69, Folder 6)
  - Nelson Atkins Museum, 2000 (Box 69, Folder 7)
  - High Museum, 2000 (Box 69, Folder 8)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Fellowship, 2001 (Box 69, Folder 9)
  - Mass MOCA, 2001 (Box 69, Folder 10)
  - Robert Lehrman re: Cornell, 2001 (Box 69, Folder 11)
  - United Kingdom, 2001 (Box 69, Folder 12)
  - Svetlana Mintcheva, PhD, 2001 (Box 70, Folder 1)
  - Kansas, 2001 (Box 70, Folder 2)
  - New Museum, 2001 (Box 70, Folder 3)
  - Paule Anglim, 2001 (Box 70, Folder 4)
  - Chicago, 2001 (Box 70, Folder 5)
  - George Quasha, 2001 (Box 70, Folder 6)
  - Carl Heyward, 2001 (Box 70, Folder 7)
  - Istanbul, 2001 (Box 70, Folder 8)
  - Cokkie Snoe Galerie Delta, 2001 (Box 70, Folder 9)
  - Vienna, 2001 (Box 70, Folder 10)
  - Minneapolis CAD & Art Omi, 2002 (Box 70, Folder 11)
  - Joanna Nathan Welles "Of Wounded Birds", 2002 (Box 70, Folder 12)
  - American Academy of Arts & Letters, 2002 (Box 70, Folder 13)
  - Kathy Acker, 2002 (Box 70, Folder 14)
  - Maria Beatty, 2002 (Box 70, Folder 15)
  - Sweden, 2002 (Box 70, Folder 16)
  - Whitebox, 2002 (Box 70, Folder 17)
  - Photo/Espana, 2002 (Box 70, Folder 18)
  - LA, 2002 (Box 70, Folder 19)
  - Palm Beach (PCIBA), 2002 (Box 71, Folder 1)
  - Madrid, 2002 (Box 71, Folder 2)
  - Whitechapel Art Gallery, 2002 (Box 71, Folder 3)
  - Darice Alexander/Baltimore Museum of Art, 2002 (Box 71, Folder 4)
  - Guild Hall Women's Art Movement, 2002 (Box 71, Folder 5)
  - Bard, 2002 (Box 71, Folder 6)
  - Vienna, 2003 (Box 71, Folder 7)
  - Three sisters (Smith, Mt. Holyoke) and Harvard, 2003 (Box 71, Folder 8)
  - Amherst, 2003 (Box 71, Folder 9)
  - One folder (CUNY, DIA Event, Elga, LA High Performance, "Gloria" Philly, ACF, Dorsky), 2003 (Box 71, Folder 10)
  - Kitchen, 2003 (Box 71, Folder 11)
  - Cal Arts [honorary degree], 2003 (Box 72, Folder 1)
  - Reykjavik, 2003 (Box 72, Folder 2)
  - John Natsoulas Gallery/Beat Generation & Beyond, 2003 (Box 72, Folder 3)
  - Library of Maps - Moira Roth, 2003 (Box 72, Folder 4)
  - Jean Touche/Jersey City Museum/Mance Research/USC/From Far Away Poems, 2003 (Box 72, Folder 5)
  - Northwestern, 2003 (Box 72, Folder 6)
  - Serra and Kathryn, 2003 (Box 72, Folder 7)
  - 9 Women In The Same Coat, Briggs Robinson Gallery, Projects, 2002-2003 (Box 72, Folder 8)
  - Eyebeam, 2003-200403 (Box 72, Folder 9)
  - Leeds, 2004 (Box 72, Folder 10)
  - Syracuse, 2004 (Box 72, Folder 11)
  - Sexy Beasts, 2004 (Box 73, Folder 1)
  - Puerto Rico, 2004 (Box 73, Folder 2)
  - McCoy Exhibit, 2004 (Box 73, Folder 3)
  - Dortmund, 2004 (Box 73, Folder 4)
  - Thanksgiving Party, 2004 (Box 73, Folder 5)
  - Interview Praxis, 2004 (Box 73, Folder 6)
  - Exhibit notes, 2004 (Box 73, Folder 7)
  - Florida, 2004-2005 (Box 73, Folder 8)
  - Museum Collectors, 2005 (Box 73, Folder 9)
  - MOCCA, 2005 (Box 73, Folder 10)
  - Agreements, 2006 (Box 73, Folder 11)
  - Spain, 2006 (Box 73, Folder 12)
  - Heide Hatry & John Wronoski, 2006-2011 (Box 73, Folder 13)
  - Angry Women, etc. [annotated drafts of writing re: CS], 2006-2011 (Box 74, Folder 1)
  - Of Interest/Underway, 2008-2011 (Box 74, Folder 2)
  - Art Institute of Chicago, 2008 (Box 74, Folder 3)
  - Reykjavik, 2008 (Box 74, Folder 4)
  - Legal, 2008 (Box 74, Folder 5)
  - Korea, 2009 (Box 74, Folder 6)
  - Ottawa, 2009 (Box 74, Folder 7)
  - Greece, 2009 (Box 74, Folder 8)
  - Le Lieu, 2009 (Box 74, Folder 9)
  - Nancy Spero reading, 2010 (Box 74, Folder 10)
  - Projects Canada - Where Are You, 2006 (Box 90, Folder 2)
  - Remy Toledo Gallery, 2004 (Box 90, Folder 4)
  - Articule, 2005 (Box 90, Folder 5)
  - Underway - Went, 2006-2008 (Box 90, Folder 6)
  - Whitechapel notebook, 2002 (Box 90, Folder 7)
  - Photi [Giovanis] (Box 90, Folder 8)
  - Special guys, 2003-2007 (Box 92, Folder 1)
  - MOCCA Toronto, 2007 (Box 92, Folder 2)
  - Jenni Knight, 2007 (Box 92, Folder 3)
  - CEPA, 2006 (Box 92, Folder 4)
  - Elga Wimmer, 2005 (Box 92, Folder 5)
  - Elga Wimmer, 2006 (Box 92, Folder 6)
  - Film LA, 2008 (Box 92, Folder 7)
  - Sydney, 2008 (Box 92, Folder 8)
  - Alice Maude-Roxby, 2006-2007 (Box 92, Folder 9)
  - Calgary, 2008 (Box 92, Folder 10)
  - Frederic Guilbard, 1999 (Box 92, Folder 11)
  - Galleries/Collectors correspondence, 1994-1995 (Box 93, Folder 1)
  - Due/overdue/done, 1999-2000 (Box 93, Folder 2)
  - Completed - due to me, 2001 (Box 93, Folder 3)
  - Publications/due to me, 1990s (Box 93, Folder 4)
  - Due/overdue/done, 1993-1994 (Box 93, Folder 5)
  - Phaidon, 1996-2000 (Box 93, Folder 6)
  - Location 1 (Box 93, Folder 7)
  - Done, 2000-2001 (Box 93, Folder 8)
  - No longer due to me, 2002-2003 (Box 93, Folder 9)
  - No longer due to me, 1997-1999 (Box 94, Folder 1)
  - Over with?, 2007-2009 (Box 94, Folder 2)
  - Guggenheim, 1999-2000 (Box 103, Folder 2)
  - CS interviews [photocopies from published sources] (Box 105, Folder 1)
  - Kristine has [correspondence] (Box 105, Folder 2)
  - 1960s Copy for C (Box 105, Folder 3)
  - Jay [Murphy] Group, 1995 (Box 105, Folder 4)
  - Volatile Huttinger (Box 105, Folder 5)
  - Max Hutchinson (Box 105, Folder 6)
  - JoAnn Wendl (Box 105, Folder 7)
  - McPherson & Co. (Box 105, Folder 8)
  - Annie Sprinkle & Pals (Box 105, Folder 9)
  - Interview With Edwin Denby (Box 105, Folder 10)
  - Lisa Cheng Gallagher - Joseph Cornell (Box 105, Folder 11)
  - Beth Hander (Box 105, Folder 12)
  - Melissa Moreton (Box 105, Folder 13)
  - Volker Hamann (Box 105, Folder 14)
  - James Schaeffer (Box 106, Folder 1-2)
  - Rebecca Schneider dissertation (Box 106, Folder 3)
  - Danielle Knafo (Box 106, Folder 4)
  - Getty (Box 106, Folder 5)
  - Photos - More Wrong Things, 2001 (Box 107, Folder 1)
  - Miriam Seidel etc. (Box 107, Folder 2)
  - PHD & Pests (Box 107, Folder 3-4)
  - Transart, Vienna (Box 107, Folder 5)
  - Misc. (Box 107, Folder 6)
  - Joseph Berke, 1996-1998 (Box 107, Folder 7)
  - Carol Berge (Box 107, Folder 8)
  - David Levi Strauss (Box 107, Folder 9)
  - Alex Juhasz Publishing, 1994-1996 (Box 108, Folder 1)
  - Publications [permissions, submission requests, etc.], 1990s (Box 108, Folder 2)
  - Release Forms - Maria Beatty & Annie Sprinkle (Box 108, Folder 3)
  - Howard Hussey, 1976-1977 (Box 108, Folder 4)
  - Meiling Cheng (Box 108, Folder 5)
  - Jack Chambers, 2002 (Box 108, Folder 6)
  - Ann Daly interview & article, 1996-1997 (Box 108, Folder 7)
  - Stiles/D.C. correspondence, 1980-1994 (Box 109, Folder 9-10)
  - Teaching jobs (Box 112, Folder 8)
  - Film (Box 112, Folder 9)
  - Terminal Velocity, 2001 (Box 112, Folder 10)
- Series 2. Project binders
  The Project binder series consists of material (photographs, slides, negatives, notes, etc.) originally in numbered three-ring binders used by Schneemann in her creative work. Most binders covered a single project, although material was frequently re-used and there are both originals and copies present. Not all binder numbers (B/N#) were used and some were assigned temporarily. The numerical sequence is mostly alphabetical by project name. B/N #94 represents scrapbooks (aka Life Books) which are described in a different series.
  - Proto Feminist Body reproductions [B/N #2] (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Transparencies from Wooden Box (B/N #4], 1950s-1970s (Box 1, Folder 2-6)
    More than 500 color and black and white negatives and slides of various sizes (8mm, 35mm, etc), numbered from #1-102 and arranged chronologically. This material includes travel shots and portraits as well as images of artworks.
  - ABC- We Print Anything - In The Cards [B/N #5], 1977 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Images and ephemera concerning the ABC exhibition, including negatives, contact sheets, and slides.
  - ABC- We Print Anything - In The Cards [B/N #6], 1977 (Box 1, Folder 8-9)
    About 50 black and white photographs of various sizes, approx. 50 color transparencies, some clippings and notes.
  - Affinity/Influence [B/N #7], 1995 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Clippings and reviews about women artists, correspondence with Danielle Leventhal, Joanna Jones.
  - Aggression for Couples [B/N #8], 1971 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    One-page typescript with minor holograph corrections, approximately six contact sheets with accompanying negatives.
  - Al Hansen Slides and Notes [B/N #9], 1995 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Contains 24 color slides, programs of a memorial concert, biography, clippings, sympathy letters, catalogue preparatory material, correspondence with Heike Lukrafka. Plus color images of CS & friends; b&w photo; 4x5 negative; b&w xeroxes; 2 Hersey candy bar wrappers.
  - Animal. Anima. Animus [B/N #10], 1998-1999 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Color slides documenting the exhibition, approximately 25 photographs, and various ephemera, plus 3x5 color negatives of “Infinity Kisses” photogrid.
  - Basic Lecture [B/N #11], 1998-1999 (Box 2, Folder 5-6)
    Notes for lectures and readings, approximately 450 as well as over 600 misc. color slides of artist's own work as well as other art works for study and teaching.
  - Body Collage [B/N #13], 1968 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Approximately 35 contact sheets with accompanying negative strips, and photographs of the performance.
  - Exhibitions [B/N #14], 2000 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    Reproductions of fliers and press releases and booklets mentioning and showcasing Carolee's work.
  - Exhibitions [B/N #15], 2000 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    Color slides, reproductions of fliers and press releases, and brief descriptions of installation pieces.
  - Selected Film & Video Works [B/N #17] (Box 3, Folder 4)
    Brief descriptions of Carolee's films.
  - Cat Scan [B/N #18], 1988 (Box 3, Folder 5-6)
    Artist's statement, review, black and white negatives, black and white and contact contact sheets, color slides, over 90 color and black and white photographs of various sizes. Photographed by Plauto.
  - Cat Scan [B/N #19], 1987 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    About 60 color and black and white photographs of various sizes, about 9 black and white transparencies, contact sheets, 5 strips of 35 mm black and white negatives, color slides with cat images and personal.
  - Cat Torture in the Liquid Gate [B/N #20], 1989 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    Performance notes, about 10 color photographs, and color slides.
  - Chicago Notebook [B/N #21], 1980 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    Blue spiral-bound quarto with holograph notes regarding the Dirty Pictures exhibition, some typescript additions laid-in.
  - Chromelodeon (4th Concretion) [B/N #22], 1963-06 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    Paper clippings, 6 black and white photographs (8" x 10"), 4 color photographs (7" x 5"), contact sheets, 35 color slides. Photos by Chuck Rothenberg.
  - Train, Plane, City Landscape [B/N #23] (Box 4, Folder 5)
    49 slides labeled "Train, Plane, City Landscape," removed from carousel.
  - Clouds [B/N #24] (Box 4, Folder 6)
    About 40 slides labeled "Clouds," removed from carousel.
  - Collectors Editions [B/N #26], late 1980s (Box 4, Folder 7)
    Carolee's correspondence with Francesco Conz, Alison Knowles, inventory sheets signed by Carolee for loans.